<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 2: Flow Resonance<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>I. The Merging of Action and Enjoyment</h2>
      <p>
        There seems to be a great resonance between the merging of action and enjoyment in Flow and OUR WORLD. The specific resonance has its origins rooted in the concept that what is required for attention in OUR WORLD is a "oneness" with the task itself. This "oneness" for the task may only be achieved in between the boundaries of the knowing and unkowing. The individual must sit in between the expert's mind and beginner's mind to extrapolate the relevant features from both.
      </p>
      <p>
        In the Beginner's mind, the task in and of itself is overwhelming. Enjoyment comes from comphrension and exploration. The beginner does not know what will ensue. This leaves the Beginner's mind curious but also fickle. Fickle to absorb and experience the irrelevant.
      </p>
      <p>
        Contrarily, the Expert's mind will not need to be bothered with such curiosity and is as such less fickle. The Expert's mind knows the paths to travel down and how things may associate. However, there is a certain inelasticity of the expert's mind with any given task. The Expert places scopes on what he may learn.
      </p>
      <p>
        Action is to the Expert's mind, as enjoyment is to the Beginner's mind. Sitting inbetween these stratifications, lies the merge. When action is enjoyment and enjoyment is action there is a certain bliss of state of mind. The task is not too easy and inelastic as the expert  would dictate and such refine his enjoyment to. As well, the task is not too hard 
      </p>
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>II. Concentraction on the Task at Hand</h2>
      <p>
        Another resonance emerges when considering Flow's concept of <b>Concentration on The Task at Hand</b>. When in flow, the individual takes note of and experiences all that is the task. What the individual does not take note of and does not experience is everything that is not the task. This certain and distinct concetration is unlike the monotonmy and concerns and distribution of attention in every day tasks and life.
      </p>
      <p>
        In the holoarchial structure of our world this sense of oneness can be understood similarily to Flow's concenreation. The holoarchial construction of our world does not place importance individual units of OUR WORLD, but merely each holon in its own distinct role. A hole can be taken in isolation, however when viewing OUR WORLD abstractlly, isolating one specific holon is not beneficial. The purpose, attention, and focus of each holon is understood in context to the other holons it is connected.
      </p>
      <p>
        The invidual holon does not matter so much as its place in the system in a grander contex does. The basketball player explains "The court - that's all that matters.." (58). That "all" that matters is the important emphasis to take note of. There maybe problems in the world, things to cognitivly process, places where attention could slip to, however for the time being those things do not matter so much. What matters is simply where and how the invidiaul, or holon, is connected to the rest.
      </p>
      <p>
        The basketball player does not value himself for some great performance, but rather is interested in the performance and concentrates on the performance in virtue of the performance itself. The invidiual is integrated into the system and out of this integration the greatest concenration emerges.
      </p>
      <p>
        Holons are connected. Each holon is in interaction and connection with its enviroment giving way to new emerging properties in a very distinct way. If you look at one holon in isolation you can take it for being an individual, in a personal sense. Each holon may have distinct properties which seperate if from all the holons in the universe of discourse, however, value is not attributed in this such fashion.
      </p>
      <p>
        The properties and value of each holon is that each holon is connected and attention is focused in our world on the one-ness and the greater sense of detachment from self. Each holon is a part of something bigger than it, itself. Concentration from each holon is understood in context of not ego, but in selflessness. The value of each holon is the connection, not the holon. Of course without the holon there would be no connection. But, the holon may only exist because of its connection.
      </p>
      <p>
        As such, the interplay of the enviroment and the unit itself gives rise to the paradgimatic concentration in OUR WORLD.
      </p>
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>III. The Loss of Self-Consciousness</h2>
      <p> 
        A final resonance between OUR WORLD can be draw with Flow's Loss of Self-Consciousness. In Flow, the sense of consciousness is lost because "there is not enough attention left over to allow a person to consider either the past or the future". Excess stimuli, waste, unrelated thought is absent because it need be absent for one to be in a true semblence with the task at hand.
      </p>
    </div>

  </body>
</html>
