<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 2: Flow Resonance<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>I. The Merging of Action and Enjoyment</h2>
      <p>
        There is a great resonance with OUR WORLD when we come to contemplate the <b>Merging of Action and Enjoyment</b> in Flow. We find that the specific resonance has its origins rooted in the concept that what is required for attention in OUR WORLD is a "oneness" with the task itself. This "oneness" with the task itself may only be achieved in between the border of knowing and unknowing. As such, the individual must sit right in between the expert's mind and beginner's mind. The individual must find the intersection of action and enjoyment for the "oneness" of the task itselfto emerge.
      </p>
      <p>
        For the Beginner's mind, the task in and of itself is overwhelming. Enjoyment is seen arising from comphrension and exploration of the unknown. The beginner does not know what will ensue in the unknown, leaving the beginner's mind curious about the unknown. The beginner finds enjoyment through the action persuing the unknown. The beginner's mind cannot understand the unknown and although enjoyment may be derived from action, there is no merging of the action and enjoyment.
      </p>
      <p>
        Contrarily, the Expert's mind will not need to be bothered with such curiosity for the unknown. The Expert's mind knows the paths to travel down and how things may associate. The expert is just curious into poking into the known. This curisioty into the known posesses a certain inelasticity of the expert's mind. The expert believes there is a clear and defined scope on what can be known. The expert goes into the game acknowledging that he knows what he knows. He may discover more to know.. but to hell with antyhing unknown for the expert has no time for anything to be classified as being truly unknown. This general attitude gives rise to action, but true enjoyment is of a diminished form and may not fully ever express itself. How can one enjoy when the enjoyment takes the scope of predefined limit and boundary.
      </p>
      <p>
        Thus, the expert's mind and the beginner's mind each have their deficincies. They do not address the semblance of action and enjoyment correctly.  Meanwhile, we acknolwedge that in flow, between the stratifications of action and enjoyment, lies the ultimate forthcoming of attention. When action is enjoyment and enjoyment is action there is a certain bliss of state of mind. The task is not too easy and inelastic as the expert's mind would dictate. Also, the task is not too hard for the beginner to derive enjoyment.  There is the shaded gray, the inbetween of action and enjoyment. The enjoyment derived from the action in and of itself. It is not extrinsic, but intrinsic. The individual persues the action because the action is instrinicly fufilling and enjoyful. There is no action and there is no enjoyment. There is just enjoyaction.
      </p>
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>II. Concentraction on the Task at Hand</h2>
      <p>
        The next resonance emerges when considering Flow's concept of <b>Concentration on The Task at Hand</b>. When in flow, the individual takes note of and experiences all that is the task. What the individual does not take note of and does not experience is everything that is not the task. This certain and distinct concentration is unlike the monotonmy, concerns, and distribution of attention in every day tasks and life.
      </p>
      <p>
        In the holoarchial structure of OUR WORLD, importance is not placed on individual units or holons of OUR WORLD. Rather, merely each holon in its own distinct role has value in its connectoins and emerging properties. A holon can be taken in isolation, however, when viewing OUR WORLD abstractly, isolating one specific holon is not necessarily the correct perspective to take. The purpose, attention, and focus of each holon is understood in context and persepctive to which other holons it is connected.
      </p>
      <p>
        As such, invidual holons do not matter as much each holon's place in the system in a grander contex does. The basketball player explains, "The court - that's all that matters.." (58). Thats "<i>all</i>" that matters is the important emphasis to take note of. There maybe problems in the world, things to cognitivly process, places where attention could slip to, however, for the time being.. those things do not matter so much. What matters is simply where and how the invidiaul, or holon, is connected to the rest.  The basketball player does not need value himself for some great performance, but rather is interested in the performance itself - as he experiences it. He does not care about credit and thus concentrates on the performance in virtue of the performance itself. The invidiual is integrated into the system through and out of this integration into the system, the greatest and most uber concentration emergees. This is unity.
      </p>
      <p>
        The Holons are intimatly connected. Each holon is in deep interaction and connection with its enviroment giving way to new emerging properties in distinctive ways. If you look at one holon in isolation you can take it for being an individual, in a personal sense. Each holon may have distinct properties which seperate it if from all the other holons in the universe of discourse, however, value is not attributed in this such fashion.  The value property of each holon is that each holon is connected and attention is focused in OUR WORLD on the oneness and the greater sense of detachment from self. Each holon is a part of something bigger than itself. Concentration from each holon is understood in context of not ego, but in selflessness. The value of each holon is in the connection, not in the holon. Of course without the holon there would be no connection. But, the holon may only exist because of its connection.
      </p>
      <p>
        As such, the interplay of the enviroment and the unit itself gives rise to the paradgimatic concentration in OUR WORLD. The purest concentration distills all else and lets us know where we stand. It need not matter much where we stand in this concentration because nothing else is thought. There is just the existential being of concentration taking way and drive.
      </p>
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <h2>III. The Loss of Self-Consciousness</h2>
      <p> 
        The final resonance between OUR WORLD is draw when considering Flow's <b>Loss of Self-Consciousness</b>. In Flow, the sense of consciousness is lost because "there is not enough attention left over to allow a person to consider either the past or the future". Excess stimuli and unrelated thought are absent from consciousness because such additional thought would impend on the task at hand. The individual becomes so conscious of the task at hand that consiousness from everything else is lost. There is exhbited a blurring of the line between the invidual and the enviroment. 
      </p>
      <p>
        Flow is an egoless thing because if any attention were to be directed at self-scruitiny or self-reflection then that attention would be diverted away from the task at hand. For the individual's mind in flow, there is only the task at hand and nothing else. The task is all that is the enviroment and the individual. There is no external enviroment and there is no real distinction to be drawn around the self. Ego is lost. Consiousness as result, is only concerned with the task and nothing else.
      </p>
      <p>
        In OUR WORLD, the loss of consciousness is observed in the true nature of the individual in OUR WORLD. The individual is not distinct or seperate from the enviroment in OUR WORLD, but the invidiaul is merely a part of OUR WORLD. OUR WORLD is of distinct value in analogy with the value of its individual constituents. In any individual in OUR WORLD, the individual in OUR WORLD may be conscious at several levels. The invidual may be conssious in regards to their own ego, self, and their place as an individual expericing OUR WORLD. The individual, altnerativly, may be conscious at the intra-personal level -- concerned with the connections between constituents of OUR WORLD. At the intra-personal level it seems as if the invidual were concious at such a level, they would need be unconsious at the self or ego level.
      </p>
      <p>
        We find that if an indviidual is truly emerged with a task and is in unity with OUR WORLD, then the self sense of consciousness is lost. There is no more conciosusness in regard to the personal realm because all that exists is the intrapersonal, the between. For the archer: the bow, the arrow, and the target is all that there is. It's just a matter of letting the arrow find its way to the target. The act is not valued and not even consious, there is a loss of consciousness in this sense. The self-consciousness is dead and it took with it all the useless strata it encompassed. It is at this point that the invididaul may truely reach beyond self and proceed to flow.
      </p>
    </div>

  </body>
</html>
