<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title">

    </div>

    <h2>The Universal Ordef of the Universe</h2>
    <p>
      Let's talk about the picture of the universal order and function of the universe. Indra's Net presents us with an interesting phenomena. We acknowledge that General Field Theory (or GFT) promotes thes holorachial organization of matter and atomoton.  But we also must decide which direction we must take our WORLD 4364. For there are extended capacities of distribution in ideological framings. You can look down path A, look down path B, and then look down path C. But which path should you take, hell if I know. Where must we go. We need start with an initial analysis, difference critique of the paths presented.
    </p>

    <p>
      The Jewel Net of Indra reveals to us something profound: down in the depths of the jewels lies a sort of metaphysical monism. Each jewels is infinity reflecting any jewel. At any critical pinpoint of the cracks of the universe, there is an infinite reflection in all directions. These reflections connect everything there is, ever was, and will ever be. There is an underlying unity we take note of. To exist. Each Jewel is blessed, with a connectedness. Pure singular solitary subtsance.
    </p>

    <p>
      Yes, but lest you forget GFT. The GFT bestows unto us a core depiction of what it is to be unitary. Monistic. Infinity through. though. For the GFT presents us with the holorichial organization of the domain of the universe. Infinite like Indra's Net. However, you need not forget ask the question: what is the virtue of the infinite scope of Indras's Net and the GFT.
    </p>

    <p>
      Does infinity transcend time? Can we put some sort of limit on this infinity. Each Jewel of Indra's Net posses and infinite reflection but at some point won't this need not end. Similarly for the GFT, how could a holorarchy even be possible. Won't there every be a fundamental building block to the universe. Yes sure, you can tear down the particals infinity, however did not God create some initial stopping point.
    </p>

    <p>
      Naw, Indra's Net posses a limit. Each Jewel by definition is an infinite gateway. But the GFT? How do we know there is not a stopping point to infinity? If God is infinite then all else is finite. And that must mean that the WORLD 4364 that God created is finite as well. Howvever, holorchial organization calls that must we consider we trancend this distinction. GFT allows us to epxress we are God. This allows for the ultimate apologia for our WORLD 4364. We are the masters of our destiny now, infinitly connected with all there ever is, was and ever will be.
    </p>

    <h2>(k)nowledge and (K)nowledge</h2>
    <p>There lies a distinct difference in the ideological approach we must take. The subjective and the objective co-exist to many's dismays. At any moment any bit, part, or the whole of the universe can be rendered as knowledge subjectivly. It is in this way we dismiss notions of a singularity or interconnectedness. Existence and perception of WORLD 4364 via GFT or Indras Net may be concieved as a mere perspective of interpretation.
    </p>
    <p>
      But above lies Indra, she constructed the Net. She had a picture, a grand picture. Did she not preach (K)nowledge in her infinity. Let's consider though that perhaps Indra, like in the GFT merely presents us with a framework for phenomonology of the self. While Indra is considered with being beyond self, she also lets us reminesce in the phenomena of the self! But let us not skimp over the issue of the fundamental unity of the self and not self. For the union of the self and not self bring about the emerging property of a new self: call this new self, self%. 
    </p>
    <p> Self% emerged from two fundamental properties and emer

    <h2>The Objective: Absolutivilty of (K)</h2>


  </body>
</html>
