<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <h2>GFT and Indra's Net</h2>
    <p>
      While contemplating the universival order of the universe, we must descend upon the ultimate apologia for our path from self to beyond self.  Yes, let us contrapose the GFT and grand old Indra's Net. General Field Theory (or GFT) promotes the holorachial organization of matter and atomoton in our universe. Alternativly, Indra's Net presents jewels infinitly reflecting upon themselves and upon all other jewels in the net. Two critically different, yet similar phenomenon of interest. Where should we take our WORLD 4364, or rather, where must we take our WORLD 4364? Grandiose extended capacities of distribution in ideological framings will emerge as we so diverge. Path A or Path B. Which shall I take? Which shall you take? Which shall WORLD 4364 take?
    </p>
    <p>
      The Jewel Net which Indra has constructed begs of us a profound question: is there truly metaphysical monism merely through the infinitism of jewel reflection? As each jewel has a property of infinitism reflecting upon every other jewel - at any critical pinpoint of the cracks of the universe, there is an denumerable and indefinite reflection to all the jewel's in Indra's net. These reflections connect everything there is, ever was, and will ever be. These connections transcend time, space, and thought. Indra's jewels are connected, the Net is connected, and we are connected. 
    </p>
    <p>
      But lest you forget GFT, wise comrade. The GFT bestows to us another depiction of what it is to be unitary and infinite. Infinity through the GFT presents us with the <i>holorichial</i> organization of the domain of the universe. Yes the GFT is infinite like Indra's Net as it calls for the whole of OUR WORLD. And to OUR WORLD we know no limits. Also the GFT does a damn good job of depicting OUR WORLD.  So who the hell is Indra and what makes her think her net can stand up to the GFT?  Indra hung her Net, however why did her Net need to be hung? When was OUR WORLD hung? Can Indra's unmotivated net hanging scope even be put in analogy with the grand GFT? We need dive deeper.
    </p>

    <p>
      Indra's Net by definition posses a limit, albeit an abitrary limit. The definition specifies that each Jewel is an infinite gateway, but each jewel is also encompassed by the net itself. The Net is the limit of the jewels. But what is the limit to OUR WORLD?  Is the denumarbility of the GFT truly infinite and thus adequete for explaning the universal order and function of our universe? Well, yes it could be rendered that way -- the holarchy incorporates all that is self and beyond self.  By what about Indra's Net? 
    </p>
    <p>
      To any specific jewel in Indra's Net, Indra is the big boss. Indra placed the jewel there and as therefore merely a slave to Indra.This is a tragedy of the highest proportion in terms of emergent properties. Indra created these jewel and immediate specified that the relation between Indra and her jewels was not holorarchical but hierarchial! What an atrocity! But we need not this distinction in OUR WORLD.  We are the masters as emerging propreties of WORLD 4364. We may have been spawned, but we need not know how or why we were spawned. We (k)now only what we (k)now.
    </p>
    <p>
      However, what does a jewel (k)now? And really was does a jewel (K)now?! Nothing. For Indra left the jewel in the dark. The net shines in the reflection of every jewel. But does Indra shine in the reflection of every jewel? OUR WORLD, seems to shine in the reflection of itself, so how can Indra even propose herself? 
    </p>

  </body>
</html>


