<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 1: The Ultimate Apologia<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <p>
      While contemplating the universival order of the universe, we must descend upon the ultimate apologia for our path from self to beyond self.  Yes, let us contrapose the GFT and the Net which Indra has constructed for us. General Field Theory (or GFT) promotes the holarchical organization of matter and automaton in our universe. Alternatively, Indra's Net presents jewels infinitely reflecting upon themselves and upon all other jewels in the net. Two critically different, yet similar phenomenon of interest. Where should we take our WORLD 4364, or rather, where must we take our WORLD 4364? Grandiose extended capacities of distribution in ideological framings will emerge as we so diverge. Path A or Path B. Which shall I take? Which shall you take? Which shall WORLD 4364 take?
    </p>
    <p>
      The Jewel Net which Indra has constructed prompts us with a profound question: can there truly be metaphysical monism merely through the infinitism of jewel reflection? As each jewel has a property of infinitism reflecting upon every other jewel - at any critical pinpoint of the cracks of the universe, there is an denumerable and indefinite reflection to all the jewel's in Indra's Net present. These reflections connect everything there is, ever was, and will ever be. These connections transcend time, space, and thought. Indra's jewels are connected, the Net is connected, and we are connected. The net ties together it all and was placed by grand old Indra. Through reflection, not only is all one, but <i>one is all</i>.
    </p>
    <p>
      But lest you forget the GFT, wise comrade. The GFT bestows to us another depiction of what it is to be unitary and infinite. Infinity through the GFT is presented to us by the <i>holarchical</i> organization of the domain of the universe. Yes, the GFT is infinite like Indra's Net as it calls for the whole of OUR WORLD at each holon to be connected holarchically. And thus, in OUR WORLD, we know no limits. The GFT does a damn good job of depicting OUR WORLD.  So now we may ask: who the hell is Indra and what makes her think that her net can stand up to the GFT?  Indra hung her Net, however why did her Net need to be hung? When was OUR WORLD hung? Can Indra's unmotivated net hanging scope even be put in analogy with the grand GFT? We need dive deeper.
    </p>

    <p>
      Indra's problem is that her net, by definition, posses a limit -- albeit an abitrary limit. Indra hung her net and specified that each Jewel is an infinite gateway, but each jewel must be encompassed by the net itself. The Net is the limit of each jewel. But what is the limit to OUR WORLD?  Is the denumerability of the GFT truly infinite and thus adequate for explaining the universal order and function of our universe? Well, yes it could be rendered that way -- the holarchy incorporates all that is self and beyond self.  But what about Indra's Net? 
    </p>
    <p>
      To any specific jewel in Indra's Net, Indra is the big boss.. GOD. Indra placed the jewel there and consequently therefore each jewel is merely a slave to Indra.This is a tragedy of the highest proportion in terms of emergent properties. Indra created these jewels and immediate specified that the relation between Indra and her jewels was not holarchical but hierarchical! Indra need be super-ordinate. What an atrocity! But we need not this distinction in OUR WORLD.  We are the masters of the emerging properties of WORLD 4364. We may have been spawned by a God like Indra, but we need not know how or why we were spawned. We (k)now only what we (k)now.
    </p>
    <p>
      But, what does a jewel (k)now? And really what does a jewel (K)now?! Nothing. For Indra left each jewel in the dark, unknowing. The net and every other jewel shines in the reflection of every jewel. However does Indra, herself, shine in the reflection of every jewel? OUR WORLD, seems to shine in the reflection in and of itself. OUR WORLD has no Indra, or if it did.. we could never (K)now. So how can Indra even propose herself? 
    </p>
    <p>
      Unlike the jewels in Indra's net, we as members of WORLD 4364 are simply holons. We are mere parts of OUR WORLD and do not stand in hierarchical organization but holarchical organization. We must self-actualize. We must understand the power the GFT bestow upon us. Reality as disclosed in so far leaves open many questions. Can Indra answer these questions? Can the Judeo-Christian God answer these questions? Can Buddha answer these questions? I think not. Reality as disclosed need be appropriated an ultimate apologia. We must embark. We need not tear down Indra's net but merely recognize it is a holon too that can be encompassed by the GFT.
    </p>
    <p>
      Thus, what we have realized is that when it comes to understanding the universal order and function of the universe - Indra will not suffice. The GFT can subsume Indra's Net and bear new emerging properties from subsumption. However, these emerging properties will not be visible by trying to comprehend the GFT from the viewpoint of Indra's Net. So we must embark with the GFT as our holy book, our guiding light, our path, as we transcend through the ultimate apologia.
    </p>

  </body>
</html>
