<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 3: Booth Ore for Our World<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <p>If we look at Eric Booth's <i>Everday Work of Art</i>, we pick up a great resonance in numerous aspects.</p>
      <p>The place where the Booth's resonance seems the greatestest is in his virtue of improvisation. Booth speaks of improvisation as an activity that Jazz musicians are skilled at. He notes however that "musicians are not the only ones who improvise. ALl of us do it every day". Its about the little things bBooth notes. Concieving of a new rout to take when we experience traffic, meeting new intreuging folk, lying for the right reasons. These interactions of our daily life shape who we are and we shape the experiences themselves. Improvisiation is not just a component of art but rather an intregral part of life itself.
      </p>
      <p>
        Booth's conception of improvisation in life hits reasonance that breaks the meter in this respect... consider the two greatest efficacies any one person to bring to any given situation.. <i>knowing</i> and <i>unknowing</i>. Rerender: <i>the expert's mind</i> and <i>the beginner's mind</i>. How else can we better follow the change affordance and thus free ourself from our self? Booth controts that: "improvisation is a fast seriaies of technical choices with personal skills... So fast is the choosing, in fact, they can't think or plan, they must rely on educated intuation". But what really is educated intution? Booth goes on to explain education intuation involves that the improviser work in the "perpetual present tense" and that this "comes with risk". Thus there is a loss of control over the activity such that unknowing and the beginners mind entails. This aspect is resonant with booth's "intution". However, the "intuition" is also "educated". Educated resonates greatly with the concept of experts mind and Knowing.
      </p>

      <p>
        Booth describes "life jazz" as "our yearinging curising the streets to find interesting stuff amid the undeveloped raw material of daily life". This concept of "life jazz" fits with conception from "flow" in that we must follow the changing affordances in any given scenario. We must be ready, willing, and intent to react to change. 

    </div>

  </body>
</html>
