<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>PSYC-3014: Homework Assignment 1</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 3: Booth Ore for Our World<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <p>Examining Eric Booth's <i>Everyday Work of Art</i>, we pick up great resonance to Our World in numerous facets. Poking along these facets we discover some rich ore lurking. Ore of different sizes, shapes, and essences. Below is a selection of the most valuable ore for Our World to examine.</p>

      <h2>In the Ordinary</h2>
      <p>
        Our world does not exist as some sort of special magnificent entity in isolation. We are in no vacuum. In fact, rather we are a vacuum, a vacuum magnet of the ordinary. Our world sucks in all of the materials, the immaterial, and the interactions. From the ordinary properties sucked in, extraordinary properties emerge. These emerging properties are magnificent: incorporating numerous components in complex fashions. These properties are though in essence... simply mundane. Just ordinary. For the only reason we see these extraordinary properties emerge is by virtuous combination of ordinary components. These components themselves are not anything special or unique. Properties interact in the vacuum and new synergy emerges. This synergy is not special, it is ordinary. The synergy of the emerging properties' limit? Multiply all the individual limits of the constituents of Our World. Nothing complex, just do some basic math.
      </p>
      <p>
        Now Booth speaks of improvisation as an activity that jazz musicians are skilled at. He notes,however that "musicians are not the only ones who improvise. All of us do it every day". Its about the little things. The details. The mundane. The ordinary. The sucking interaction. You conceive of a new route to take when in traffic, you meet a new intriguing folk, you lie in cold blood for the right reasons. These are the automatized interactions of daily life. The interactions shape who we are but we don't consider them as doing so.  These mundane, simple, minute interactions are grounding and define the scope of "life jazz". It does not feel like art but this "life jazz" encompasses "our yearning cruising the streets to find interesting stuff amid the undeveloped raw material of daily life". The dynamics of the nature in which we interact need requires us to follow the changing affordances. We adjust, act, react.  We consider ourselves artists. But some don't consider themselves artists, but I can still consider them artists without their approval. I see it all as extraordinary because the emergent properties are overwhelming. Tucked beneath it all though is the ordinary.
      </p>

      <h2>Navigation through Our World</h2>
      <p>
        Following the changing affordances in life and art in our world can be seen as a sort of navigational quest. As we take this quest through our world there is: action and then reaction. Action occurs, then reaction is needed to balance the changing affordances dictated by said action.  Booth describes this navigational sequence as: "world making is a series of absorbing improvasitionary process with some sort of shape.... with an inherent spontaneous bounce that sparks further world-work".  Booth notes that there is "shape" to our quest, but what might this shape look like? To this Booth comments that "the upside of expectation is an optimistic reaching toward the future... also evident in acting training". In this navigational question we must be have "readiness" to receive and dynamically react to the curves of the path. As such, we may navigate through our world, but our path is not "set in stone" or known. To be fully actualized you must accept the realization that perhaps even if the statue was in the stone we must let this path organically grow. Further, it seems like we don't control this organic growth of this path, or if we do its not fully conscious control.
      </p>
      <p>
        As such, if you asked Michelangelo before he chiseled the stone what the statue might look like as a finalized "product",  he would daze at you in a glare with eyes as wide as watermelons. Then he would proceed to hallow to you, "when I chisel it I will know sir" or something along those lines. Now you see, this shape we may consider for the path through our world is not something that can be prospectively define or "set". Or at least if we seek the fullest truest actualization in our world, this is not a feasible expectation. In fact, we need our expectations to be malleable and be ready to make the "technical choices" rooted in "educated intuition".  Thus, as we talk about getting a fuller truer world actualization, we need only a guide.  The shape, the path, and our dissent may be only equipped with at best a metaphorical compass. Booth tells us we shalt not "hammer-thump" but merely "transform, redirect, understand, use, extract value from the sequence of opportunities called daily life". Life and art live in the perpetual present in flux, changing, growing, shrinking, and possibly most fitting: morphing.
      </p>

      <h2>Dialogue in Art and Life</h2>
      <p>
        Booth notes that "art is made in dialogue". The challenge for the artist is to listen, carefully digest, and comprehend the actively changing dialogue between "what it needs" to be and what it "wants to be". The artist need understand "worlds take on a life of their own, develop their own rules and requirements, and artists have the sensitivity to attend to such subtleties". As such, emerging properties of the dynamic interplay between "what it needs" and what it "wants to be" expand from the soil to prompt us what we as artists, citizens, comrades to balance. Filter out the complex dialogue between the two components and you will derive something intrinsically valuable to the art itself. Silence what it wants to be and you will look at only the end goal. What you came into it thinking it "should" be. You dismiss the unknown, new and novel emerging properties that come in virtue of the interplay of process itself. You consider the ends but care not about the means.
      </p>
      <p>
        Contrarily, you may let the art dictate and immerse yourself in the experience disregarding what "what it needs" and merely focusing on "wants to be" and you deprive the art from any sort of higher purpose. The art is valuable in and of itself and the process but what is that to the external. You build the island, let it grow and organically self determine itself. It says I want to be round, you make it round. It says I want to be surrounded with only the freshest water, you give it only the freshest water. Then you have this isolated island, a peninsula of despair you cannot seem to escape. You take a stroll along the island. You ask the native fisherman to figure out what it is he may need to better and more truly fish his fish. He responds to you "I've got my fishing rod. And this island is wonderful. But it is what it is". As the existential tidbit from the fisherman subsumes your thought, your psyche collapses under its own weight. It is only what it is, and that is the worst thing that could happen. You places limits, but arbitrary limits albeit that "you" in a sense did not dictate. You were not in true. You were a slave to what it wanted to be.
      </p>
      <p>
        As such we find this <i>dialogue</i> between "what it needs" and what it "wants to be" is an invaluable thing. This dialogue is something to take careful note of, to cherish, "attend moment-to-moment without zooming off". It is easier said than done, but if the dialogue may be facilitated in the proper manner for the art, life interaction, essence then that "spontaneous bounce" will "spark further world-work". And that is all we want. The dialogue allows us to eavesdrop. To understand how we can go about balancing the unknowing and the knowing. This dialogue urges us to "perceive the extraordinary in the ordinary".  When we are experts at perceiving the extraordinary in the ordinary we can then move to see the ordinary extraordinary. We move between the known and unknown. We become the great sliders of section.
      </p>

    </div>

  </body>
</html>
