<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>WORLD Project 4</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 4: Maslow's Creative Attitude and Us<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      Scanning of Maslow's creative attitude, we find great resonances with Our World. 
      Maslow speaks of a sense in which he regards creative endaevors as the the artist must "loses his past and his future and lives only in the moment". 

      Maslow also notes that there is a "fusion with the reality being observed". In this such state Maslow states that there is a oneness where there was a twoness. 

      There is resonance with flow in Maslows work as well in the section in which he notes that "one main characteristic of the peak experience is just this total fasination with the matter-in-hand, this getting lost in the present, this detachment from time and place. And it seems to me now that much of what we have learned from the study of these peak experiences can be experiences, even though it now szemes clear that pracitcally all people can report moments of rapture if they dig around long enough."

      Loss of ego is a central component of Maslow's creative attitude. In the creative attitude less self-awareness is present as you are absorbed with the enviroment completly. You do not use the outside critical view but are rather simply one with the enviroment.  Further, your ego is modified in such a way that your serlf-observing ego and your experiencing ego become dissperate. You loose consciousness of your self, you do not think about your ego and the things you are experiencing as if you are an observer on the scence. Rather you may observe from afar your very eog and the things you are experiencing.   


      Ther eis a certain pliacnu of action int he person in the creative attidue eh
      There is a certain pliancy of action in the person in the creative attitude such that they may comprend 
    </div>

  </body>
</html>
