<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>WORLD Project 4</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 4: Maslow's Creative Attitude and Us<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <p>
        Maslow's <i>Creative Attitude</i> calls for the artist to embrace a state of perpetual present in which the past and the future seem to fade <i>into the present</i>. Maslow states that the artist "loses his past and his future and lives only in the moment" (p.59). This loss of the past and the future to live only in the moment does not imply that the artist no longer has any conception of the past and future; rather the present is so engaging that it seems the past and the future have in a sense merged into the present. As such, the present as it is normally experienced is not what is revealed to the participant; rather the present that is experienced and revealed to the participant in the creative attitude arises with a sense of total absorption in the "here-now, with the matter at hand" (p.59). However, while the sense in which the artist experiencing a unity with this new present transcends temporal distinction, Maslow notes additionally that there is fusion with "reality being observed" (p.60).  This taking note of reality being observed allows the individual in the creative attitude to understand the place in the worlds which he occupies.
      </p>
      <p>
        Taking note of reality as observed and thus understanding one's place in the world requires the creator to follow the changing affordance relationships being played out. As psychological paradigms are being played out, the participant becomes mindful and observant of all the changing affordances and bring his efficacies forthworth. A sense of un-wavering attention is channeled forth from the participant to the environment, the environment responds, and "peak experience" ensues (p.60). There becomes detachment from place and time and all that the participant normally is concerned with in the monotony of daily life because the world in which he is participating has absorbed him. This absorption into the world in which the participant is engaged gives rise to a sense of unwavering attention such that the participant has becomes more fully and truly actualized with the transpersonal realm which he is being engaged.
      </p>
      <p>
        In Maslow's creative attitude there is additionally a loss of self. Being less in touch with or concerned with everything that is not the matter at hand; we loose sense of the associations and the worlds which we occupy in context to other people. We for the moment loose others "ties to us and ours to them, of obligations, duties, fears, hopes, etc." (p.62). In the creative attitude, our consciousness is narrowed to only channel its focus in one particular direction. As such, we become incapable of our normal obsession with concept of what we might "be" and rather think only about the relation with have with our task. Maslow extends this notion to state that we become our "real self" and allow ourselves a newly found innocence (p.63). We are free to act like a child once again, "free of influence of other people in such moment", however this sense in which we act like a child is not in virtue of ignorance. Rather, this sense in which we gain innocence becomes a newly found deep insight.
      </p>
      <p>
        The participant is re-exposed to beginners mind, releases his assumptions as he escapes and drops his mask. We realize that we no longer have "audience to play to" and thus we "cease to be actors" (p.63). We become more fully and truly actualized by detaching ourselves from the meta-analysis of the situation and come to appreciate and become engulfed in the situation itself. We understand the self-stabilizing nature of the world in which we are occupied as we channel our attention and thus devote our full transpersonal selves "to the problem" (p.63). By devoting ourselves simply to the problem and actualizing the greater sense of self to the world, consciousness slips away as well.  The conscious outsider, critical view, of one's own ego fades because the ego is transformed from being in nature meta-analytical to the experience disclosed to rather simply being an "<i>all</i> experiencing ego" (p.63). While in normal ego perspective, one normally and regularly critiques one's own ego as a manifestation of "the painful awareness of being looked at", in the creative attitude this disposition is not present. Rather, the self has transcended notions of judgment as such a notion of judgment is only helpful in solving the current problem, focusing one's attention, and devoting oneself fully to the present world and reality as it is being disclosed.
      </p>
      <p>
        Consciousness is realized to be an inhibiting force because of the doubt, analysis, and conflicts it brings with it. Consciousness need always be consciousness of something, and as such ego is an object of consciousness that carries with is significant weight. Consciousness of self in the creative attitude is not present and this is a necessary absence because it allows an emerging "spontaneity and of expressiveness" (p.63). With "self-observating-and-criticizing" faded away in Maslow's creative attitude, we see an emergence of effortless effort (p.64) Our efficacies which we have brought to the situation, strength, courage, a certain "stubbornness, independence, self-sufficiency, a kind of arrogance" has allowed us to transcend fears and defense responses (p.64). We no longer suffer from fears, meta-cognition concerning the bigger picture or dimensions outside of our immediate matrix connections, but rather we are greeted with strength. The here and now consumes us and our utter completely devotion and absorption to the experience casts outs all fears.
      </p>
      <p>
        In true, we surrender to the "matter-in-hand here-now" and let the intrinsic nature of the situation dictate the course of our action. Our ego fades away as we employ a new "trust in the self and trust in the world" allowing ourselves to be free of "conscious coping and effort" (p.65). We allow the dynamic interplay of beginner's mind and expert's mind to interact freely in their own nature and do not try and specify hard and rigid guidelines to which our action must adhere. We <i>trust</i> rather than <i>try</i> and <i>effort</i> simply becomes <i>effortless</i>. The participant no longer has desire to dominate because the true nature of the field occupied has been revealed. Once revealed and new sense of innocence is presented, trust leads the way in an almost unconscious fashion. It is a feeling that is transcendent in such that we just let happen what we need to happen. Maslow notes that this transcendence and pliancy seen in the creative attitude is not too hard to recognize even in our daily lives citing examples such as: "giving birth, urination, defecation, sleeping, floating in the water" (p.65). These types of activities are such that if we try to <i>exert</i> effort there is no direct feedback. We must just let ourselves freely be in the situation and not try to control the situation. When we manage to reach the state of affair in that we just let it be, we come to realize the sense of effortless effort and it is a thing of glory. We become enamored with its beauty, drive, and pull. We are a part of it and it is on a large scale a wonderful feeling.
      </p>

      <p>
        In the creative attitude, the participant has a great sense of respect for the here and now of the situation at hand. We see the reality as disclosed and understand both its great significance and its utter insignificance as this allows us to put forth a kind of "courtesy or defense" (p.66). The artist does not treat the materials as means to an end, but rather as ends in and of themselves. This courtesy allows us to see the nature of the reality being disclosed in its fullest and truest nature and such it gives rise to a new found sense of appreciation.  This appreciation allows us to see the sense in which the here and now of the situation, the reality as disclosed is part of a great eco-biological organization. We bring our efficacies to the situation and may follow the changing affordances because we see the "creativeness is... systematic ; ie.e, a whole - or Gestalt" (p.66). We recognize the quality and situation not in the sense that it needs organization or we add to it "like a coat of paint or like an invasion of bacteria" (p.66). Rather, Maslow notes that this sense in which we realize the holistic nature of phenomena is the "opposite of dissociation" (p.66). We recognize the phenomena of the situation, the subject, the object, but more so the nature of the subject times the object.
      </p>
      <p>
        Seeing the nature of the subject times the object, we perceive aesthetically rather than abstractly. The end-product is not as important as the "phenomenological reality itself" and take realization in the aesthetic value of the here and now itself. We need not abstract from the reality being disclosed to us, as "the map is <i>not</i> the territory" (p.67). Rather, we need recognize what the phenomena affords  us. Maslow notes this fascination "with it for its own sake" lets its all flow out of us (p.67). We are not controlling but rather thinking only of our god. Thinking only of our god grants us a new sense of the fullest possible spontaneity. Without consciousness, we may act with effortless effort, we may exert, without control, we may follow our instinct. We take note of all the phenomenological reality being disclosed and we are guided by the changing affordances to which we know exactly what to do. We let expert and beginners mind interact in their dynamic interplay and continuously and effortlessly adapt "as the situation changes" (p.67).
      </p>
      <p>
        In this creative attitude, we have the fullest expressiveness because we give only honest and true expression of the "nature and the style of the freely functioning organism, and of its uniqueness" (p.67). We let ourselves be a part of the great matrices and let ourselves be situated in our world more intrue. Only concerned with the "intrinsic nature of the matter-in-hand, the instrinsic nature of the person and the intrinsic necessities", we become free. Guided, uninhibited, and uncontrolled we have no extrinsic ends, only ends in and of themselves. Through this creative attitude, great transpersonal self actualization is facilitated through world actualization. The self has become incorporated into the world in which is its guidelines. The senses of self, separation, close-mindedness, rigidness, and borders have faded. Through not trying to control the situation, one in the creative attitude has transcended to another level of consciosuness. This new level of conciousness is great and things we used to see as barriers or obstacles become simply a part of the process and continuum. By becoming part of the world, we have become more fully and truly actualized as we have transcended self beyond self.
      </p>
      </div>
  </body>
</html>
