<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML 1.0 Strict//EN" "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml1/DTD/xhtml1-strict.dtd">
<html>
  <head>
    <title>WORLD Project 4</title>
    <meta name="author" content="Miles Sandlar"/>
    <meta name="date"   content="2012-10-08"/>
    <link rel="stylesheet" src="format.css" />
  </head>
  <body>
    <div id="title" >
      WORLD 4364 - Project 4: Maslow's Creative Attitude and Us<br/><br/>
      "I have neither given nor received unauthorized assistance on this assignment."<br/>
      Miles Sandlar
    </div>
    <div class="entry">
      <p>
        Maslow's <i>Creative Attitude</i> contains much resonance with Our World. 
      </p>


      <p>
        Maslow speaks of a sense in which he attributes that creative endaevors require the artist must "loses his past and his future and lives only in the moment". This does not mean that the artist no longer has conception of the past and the future, but rather they are integrated into the present. There concepts of past, preent, and future are not seperabel isolatable entities but rather seen in a larger contiuum of action. This mereging of past, present, and future can be seen to give rise to a new emerging property; a new sense of "present". The new sense of "present" in which there is a "fusion with the reality being observed". 
      </p>
      <p>
        This sense in which Malow offers that there is a loss of past and future hits an incredible resonance with the second lesser frame of the holarchical organization of OUR WORLD:  the phenomonogocal field. The phenomoonological field calls for a re-identification of our world from the persepctive of reality as disclosed. What reality disclosed hints at is not that we are like observers watching a cinema as the story is being disclosed but we are actors in the cinema. We are part of the phenomological field and presence that exists. The subject and object are not disseprate things but merely part of a bigger world.  In this such reasoning, "there is a oneness where there was a twoness". While outside of the creative attitude, one may view a subject as being seperate and distinct from the object. While in the creative attitude, like in the phenomological frame of Our World, there is no seperate subject and artist. An artist does not think about his creation outside of the virtue of the act of its creation; but rather the artist thinks only of his act.
      </p>

      <p>
        There is resonance with flow in Maslow's <i>Creative Attitude</i> as well. Maslow notes one of the primary charactistic's of "peak experience" is "total fasination with the matter-in-hand". In this peak experience, we get completly enamoured and lost in the present because we see it as the source of all that is relevant at that moment. In the <i>task at hand</i>, we recognize and observe all of the phenoma of the situation with the pliancy of beginners but the suddle edging of expert's mind.  Maslow notes that "we become less conscious of every other than the matter at hand" and further that "If we have no audience to play to, we cease to be actors". We are no longer outside observers, but integrated.  In this peak experience that there is a sense of "innoence" such that the particpant enters the stiatuion "wihout a priori expections,...shoulds...oughts,,, without fashions, fads, dogmas, habits" and so on. The external of the given situation does not play into the relevance into the task.  This is similar to the situation with the archer "letting the arrow find the target". The archer reported to simply "let the arrow" find its target. The archer before shooting the arrow did not think about he <i>himself</i>, as a subject, needed to let the arrow find the way to the target. Rather, the archer realized the world he was operating in such that he simply let the arrow find the target.
      </p>
      <p>
        . And it seems to me now that much of what we have learned from the study of these peak experiences can be experiences, even though it now szemes clear that pracitcally all people can report moments of rapture if they dig around long enough."
      </p>

      <p>
        Loss of ego is a central component of Maslow's creative attitude. In the creative attitude less self-awareness is present as you are absorbed with the enviroment completly. You do not use the outside critical view but are rather simply one with the enviroment.  Your ego is modified in such a way that your self-observing ego and your experiencing ego become dissperate. You loose consciousness of your self, you do not think about your ego and the things you are experiencing as if you are an outside observer of the scence. Rather you may observe from afar your old "normal" experienced ego as something that has been trasncended. In this sense of loss of ego we can see great reasonance with the phenomonlogical snse of our self incorporation into something different from ouselves. In this sense, understood from Heidegger's perspective we may render and understand our ego simply from the siense in with we are "relating to onself by being with beings"
      </p>
      <p>
        There is a certain pliancy of action in the person in the creative attitude such that they may comprend 
      </p>

      <p>
        Worth note is the respectfullness of the artist in the world he occupies. Maslow explains that an artist must have respect for his materials "as a paradigm". This is similar to taking the craft seriously, in which the craft is held in virtue of the materials should be treated not as a means, but as an end. The materials are not just the means to get to the end goal, not to be used as a tool "for some extrinsic purpose" but rather as an intergral part of the enviroment and part of the grander scheme. This sense of respectfulness to the materials is an emerging property which bears incredible resemblance to the sense in which Our World need recognize the value in its constiuents. We are comrades in Our World each of whom we treat eachother with a very large amount of respect.
      </p>


    </div>

  </body>
</html>
